<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="null"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Ready Player One</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   <xenoData><rdf:RDF xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#" xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#" xmlns:as="http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#" xmlns:cwrc="http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/" xmlns:geo="http://www.geonames.org/ontology#" xmlns:oa="http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#" xmlns:schema="http://schema.org/" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#" xmlns:fabio="https://purl.org/spar/fabio#" xmlns:bf="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#" xmlns:cito="https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#" xmlns:org="http://www.w3.org/ns/org#">
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zbb5/courses/main/HUMN100_SP-2024/ReadyPlayerOne.xml?person_annotation_20240304092022906",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2024-03-04T14:20:22.906Z",
	"dcterms:modified": "2024-03-04T14:20:22.906Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/zbb5",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "Zach Blumenfeld"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zbb5/courses/main/HUMN100_SP-2024/ReadyPlayerOne.xml?person_annotation_20240304092022906#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zbb5/courses/main/HUMN100_SP-2024/ReadyPlayerOne.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zbb5/courses/main/HUMN100_SP-2024/ReadyPlayerOne.xml?person_annotation_20240304092022906#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/p/persName"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": [
			"schema:Person",
			"cwrc:FictionalPerson"
		],
		"@id": "http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q55808133",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
	},
	"cwrc:hasCertainty": "cwrc:high"
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      
        <rdf:Description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/TR/json-ld/">
          <![CDATA[{
	"@context": {
		"dcterms:created": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:created"
		},
		"dcterms:issued": {
			"@type": "xsd:dateTime",
			"@id": "dcterms:issued"
		},
		"oa:motivatedBy": {
			"@type": "oa:Motivation"
		},
		"@language": "en",
		"rdf": "http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#",
		"rdfs": "http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#",
		"as": "http://www.w3.org/ns/activitystreams#",
		"cwrc": "http://sparql.cwrc.ca/ontologies/cwrc#",
		"dc": "http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/",
		"dcterms": "http://purl.org/dc/terms/",
		"foaf": "http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/",
		"geo": "http://www.geonames.org/ontology#",
		"oa": "http://www.w3.org/ns/oa#",
		"schema": "http://schema.org/",
		"xsd": "http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#",
		"fabio": "https://purl.org/spar/fabio#",
		"bf": "http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/bif#",
		"cito": "https://sparontologies.github.io/cito/current/cito.html#",
		"org": "http://www.w3.org/ns/org#"
	},
	"id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zbb5/courses/main/HUMN100_SP-2024/ReadyPlayerOne.xml?place_annotation_20240304092148949",
	"type": "oa:Annotation",
	"dcterms:created": "2024-03-04T14:21:48.949Z",
	"dcterms:modified": "2024-03-04T14:21:48.949Z",
	"dcterms:creator": {
		"@id": "https://github.com/zbb5",
		"@type": [
			"cwrc:NaturalPerson",
			"schema:Person"
		],
		"cwrc:hasName": "Zach Blumenfeld"
	},
	"oa:motivatedBy": "oa:identifying",
	"oa:hasTarget": {
		"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zbb5/courses/main/HUMN100_SP-2024/ReadyPlayerOne.xml?place_annotation_20240304092148949#Target",
		"@type": "oa:SpecificResource",
		"oa:hasSource": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zbb5/courses/main/HUMN100_SP-2024/ReadyPlayerOne.xml",
			"@type": "dctypes:Text",
			"dc:format": "text/xml"
		},
		"oa:renderedVia": {
			"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
			"@type": "as:Application",
			"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
			"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
		},
		"oa:hasSelector": {
			"@id": "https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zbb5/courses/main/HUMN100_SP-2024/ReadyPlayerOne.xml?place_annotation_20240304092148949#Selector",
			"@type": "oa:XPathSelector",
			"rdf:value": "TEI/text/body/p[3]/placeName"
		}
	},
	"oa:hasBody": {
		"@type": "cwrc:RealPlace",
		"@id": "http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q2",
		"dc:format": "text/plain"
	},
	"as:generator": {
		"@id": "https://leaf-writer.leaf-vre.org",
		"@type": "as:Application",
		"rdfs:label": "LEAF-Writer",
		"schema:url": "https://leaf-writer.lincsproject.ca/",
		"schema:softwareVersion": "3.4.0"
	}
}]]>
        </rdf:Description>
      </rdf:RDF></xenoData></teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>Everyone my age remembers where they were and what they were doing when they first
            heard about the contest. I was sitting in my hideout watching cartoons when the news
            bulletin broke in on my video feed, announcing that <persName key="James Halliday" ref="http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q55808133" cert="high" type="fictional">James Halliday</persName> had died during the
            night.</p>
         <p>I’d heard of Halliday, of course. Everyone had. He was the videogame designer
            responsible for creating <placeName cert="high" type="virtual">the OASIS</placeName>, a massively multiplayer on- line game that had
            gradually evolved into the globally networked virtual reality most of humanity now used
            on a daily basis. The unprecedented success of the OASIS had made Halliday one of the
            wealthiest people in the world.</p>
         <p>At first, I couldn’t understand why the media was making such a big deal of the
            billionaire’s death. After all, the people of <placeName key="Earth" ref="http://www.wikidata.org/entity/Q2">Planet Earth</placeName> had other concerns. The
            ongoing energy crisis. Catastrophic climate change. Widespread famine, poverty, and
            disease. Half a dozen wars. You know: “dogs and cats living together . . . mass
            hysteria!” Normally, the news- feeds didn’t interrupt everyone’s interactive sitcoms and
            soap operas un- less something really major had happened. Like the outbreak of some new
            killer virus, or another major city vanishing in a mushroom cloud. Big stuff like that.
            As famous as he was, Halliday’s death should have war- ranted only a brief segment on
            the evening news, so the unwashed masses could shake their heads in envy when the
            newscasters announced the ob- scenely large amount of money that would be doled out to
            the rich man’s heirs.</p>

         <p>But that was the rub. James Halliday had no heirs. He had died a sixty-seven-year-old
            bachelor, with no living relatives and, by most accounts, without a single friend. He’d
            spent the last fifteen years of his life in self-imposed isolation, during which time—if
            the ru- mors were to be believed—he’d gone completely insane.</p>
         <p>So the real jaw-dropping news that January morning, the news that had everyone from
            Toronto to Tokyo crapping in their cornfl akes, con- cerned the contents of Halliday’s
            last will and testament, and the fate of his vast fortune.</p>
         <p>Halliday had prepared a short video message, along with instructions that it be released
            to the world media at the time of his death. He’d also ar- ranged to have a copy of the
            video e-mailed to every single OASIS user that same morning. I still remember hearing
            the familiar electronic chime when it arrived in my inbox, just a few seconds after I
            saw that fi rst news bulletin.</p>
         <p>His video message was actually a meticulously constructed short fi lm titled Anorak’s
            Invitation. A famous eccentric, Halliday had harbored a lifelong obsession with the
            1980s, the decade during which he’d been a teenager, and Anorak’s Invitation was crammed
            with obscure ’80s pop culture references, nearly all of which were lost on me the fi rst
            time I viewed it.</p>
         <p>The entire video was just over fi ve minutes in length, and in the days and weeks that
            followed, it would become the most scrutinized piece of fi lm in history, surpassing
            even the Zapruder fi lm in the amount of pains- taking frame-by-frame analysis devoted
            to it. My entire generation would come to know every second of Halliday’s message by
            heart.</p>

         <figure/>

         <p>Anorak’s Invitation begins with the sound of trumpets, the opening of an old song called
            “Dead Man’s Party.”</p>
         <p>The song plays over a dark screen for the fi rst few seconds, until the trumpets are
            joined by a guitar, and that’s when Halliday appears. But he’s not a
            sixty-seven-year-old man, ravaged by time and illness. He looks just as he did on the
            cover of Time magazine back in 2014, a tall, thin, healthy man in his early forties,
            with unkempt hair and his trademark horn-rimmed eyeglasses. He’s also wearing the same
            clothing he wore in the Time cover photo: faded jeans and a vintage Space Invaders
            T-shirt.</p>
         <p>Halliday is at a high-school dance being held in a large gymnasium. He’s surrounded by
            teenagers whose clothing, hairstyles, and dance moves all indicate that the time period
            is the late 1980s. <note>Careful analysis of this scene reveals that all of the
               teenagers behind Halliday are actu- ally extras from various John Hughes teen fi lms
               who have been digitally cut-and-pasted into the video.</note> Halliday is dancing,
            too— something no one ever saw him do in real life. Grinning maniacally, he spins in
            rapid circles, swinging his arms and head in time with the song, flawlessly cycling
            through several signature ’80s dance moves. But Halli- day has no dance partner. He is,
            as the saying goes, dancing with himself.</p>
         <p>A few lines of text appear briefly at the lower left-hand corner of the screen, listing
            the name of the band, the song’s title, the record label, and the year of release, as if
            this were an old music video airing on MTV: Oingo Boingo, “Dead Man’s Party,” MCA
            Records, 1985.</p>
         <p>When the lyrics kick in, Halliday begins to lip-synch along, still gyrat- ing: “All
            dressed up with nowhere to go. Walking with a dead man over my shoulder. Don’t run away,
            it’s only me. . . .”</p>
         <p>He abruptly stops dancing and makes a cutting motion with his right hand, silencing the
            music. At the same moment, the dancers and the gym- nasium behind him vanish, and the
            scene around him suddenly changes.</p>
         <p>Halliday now stands at the front of a funeral parlor, next to an open casket. <note>His
               surroundings are actually from a scene in the 1989 fi lm Heathers. Halliday appears
               to have digitally re-created the funeral parlor set and then inserted himself into
               it.</note> A second, much older Halliday lies inside the casket, his body emaciated
            and ravaged by cancer. Shiny quarters cover each of his eyelids. <note>High-resolution
               scrutiny reveals that both quarters were minted in 1984.</note></p>
         <p>The younger Halliday gazes down at the corpse of his older self with mock sadness, then
            turns to address the assembled mourners. <note>The mourners are actually all actors and
               extras from the same funeral scene in Heathers. Winona Ryder and Christian Slater are
               clearly visible in the audience, sitting near the back.</note> Halliday snaps his fi
            ngers and a scroll appears in his right hand. He opens it with a fl ourish and it
            unfurls to the fl oor, unraveling down the aisle in front of him. He breaks the fourth
            wall, addressing the viewer, and begins to read.</p>
         <p>“I, James Donovan Halliday, being of sound mind and disposing mem- ory, do hereby make,
            publish, and declare this instrument to be my last will and testament, hereby revoking
            any and all wills and codicils by me at any time heretofore made. . . .” He continues
            reading, faster and faster, plowing through several more paragraphs of legalese, until
            he’s speaking so rapidly that the words are unintelligible. Then he stops abruptly.
            “For- get it,” he says. “Even at that speed, it would take me a month to read the whole
            thing. Sad to say, I don’t have that kind of time.” He drops the scroll and it vanishes
            in a shower of gold dust. “Let me just give you the highlights.” </p>
         <p>The funeral parlor vanishes, and the scene changes once again. Hal- liday now stands in
            front of an immense bank vault door. “My entire es- tate, including a controlling share
            of stock in my company, Gregarious Simulation Systems, is to be placed in escrow until
            such time as a single condition I have set forth in my will is met. The fi rst
            individual to meet that condition will inherit my entire fortune, currently valued in
            excess of two hundred and forty billion dollars.”</p>
         <p>The vault door swings open and Halliday walks inside. The interior of the vault is
            enormous, and it contains a huge stack of gold bars, roughly the size of a large house.
            “Here’s the dough I’m putting up for grabs,” Halliday says, grinning broadly. “What the
            hell. You can’t take it with you, right?”</p>
         <p>Halliday leans against the stack of gold bars, and the camera pulls in tight on his
            face. “Now, I’m sure you’re wondering, what do you have to do to get your hands on all
            this moolah? Well, hold your horses, kids. I’m getting to that. . . .” He pauses
            dramatically, his expression changing to that of a child about to reveal a very big
            secret.</p>
         <p>Halliday snaps his fi ngers again and the vault disappears. In the same instant,
            Halliday shrinks and morphs into a small boy wearing brown corduroys and a faded The
            Muppet Show T-shirt. <note>Halliday now looks exactly as he did in a school photo taken
               in 1980, when he was eight years old.</note> The young Halliday stands in a cluttered
            living room with burnt orange carpeting, wood- paneled walls, and kitschy late-’70s
            decor. A 21-inch Zenith television sits nearby, with an Atari 2600 game console hooked
            up to it.</p>
         <p>“This was the fi rst videogame system I ever owned,” Halliday says, now in a child’s
            voice. “An Atari 2600. I got it for Christmas in 1979.” He plops down in front of the
            Atari, picks up a joystick, and begins to play. “My favorite game was this one,” he
            says, nodding at the TV screen, where a small square is traveling through a series of
            simple mazes. “It was called Adventure. Like many early videogames, Adventure was
            designed and programmed by just one person. But back then, Atari refused to give its
            programmers credit for their work, so the name of a game’s creator didn’t actually
            appear anywhere on the packaging.” On the TV screen, we see Halliday use a sword to slay
            a red dragon, although due to the game’s crude low-resolution graphics, this looks more
            like a square using an arrow to stab a deformed duck.</p>
         <p>“So the guy who created Adventure, a man named Warren Robinett, decided to hide his name
            inside the game itself. He hid a key in one of the game’s labyrinths. If you found this
            key, a small pixel-sized gray dot, you could use it to enter a secret room where
            Robinett had hidden his name.” On the TV, Halliday guides his square protagonist into
            the game’s secret room, where the words created by warren robinett appear in the cen-
            ter of the screen.</p>
         <p>“This,” Halliday says, pointing to the screen with genuine reverence, “was the very fi
            rst videogame Easter egg. Robinett hid it in his game’s code without telling a soul, and
            Atari manufactured and shipped Adventure all over the world without knowing about the
            secret room. They didn’t fi nd out about the Easter egg’s existence until a few months
            later, when kids all over the world began to discover it. I was one of those kids, and
            fi nding Robinett’s Easter egg for the fi rst time was one of the coolest videogaming
            experiences of my life.”</p>
         <p>The young Halliday drops his joystick and stands. As he does, the liv- ing room fades
            away, and the scene shifts again. Halliday now stands in a dim cavern, where light from
            unseen torches fl ickers off the damp walls.</p>
         <p>In the same instant, Halliday’s appearance also changes once again, as he morphs into
            his famous OASIS avatar, Anorak—a tall, robed wizard with a slightly more handsome
            version of the adult Halliday’s face (minus the eyeglasses). Anorak is dressed in his
            trademark black robes, with his ava- tar’s emblem (a large calligraphic letter “A”)
            embroidered on each sleeve.</p>
         <p>“Before I died,” Anorak says, speaking in a much deeper voice, “I cre- ated my own
            Easter egg, and hid it somewhere inside my most popular videogame—the OASIS. The fi rst
            person to fi nd my Easter egg will in- herit my entire fortune.”</p>
         <p>Another dramatic pause.</p>
         <p>“The egg is well hidden. I didn’t just leave it lying under a rock some- where. I
            suppose you could say that it’s locked inside a safe that is bur- ied in a secret room
            that lies hidden at the center of a maze located somewhere”—he reaches up to tap his
            right temple—“up here.</p>
         <p>“But don’t worry. I’ve left a few clues lying around to get everyone started. And here’s
            the fi rst one.” Anorak makes a grand gesture with his right hand, and three keys
            appear, spinning slowly in the air in front of him. They appear to be made of copper,
            jade, and clear crystal. As the keys continue to spin, Anorak recites a piece of verse,
            and as he speaks each line, it appears briefl y in fl aming subtitles across the bottom
            of screen:</p>

         <lg>
            <l>Three hidden keys open three secret gates</l>
            <l>Wherein the errant will be tested for worthy traits</l>
            <l>And those with the skill to survive these straits</l>
            <l>Will reach The End where the prize awaits</l>
         </lg>

         <p>As he finishes, the jade and crystal keys vanish, leaving only the copper key, which now
            hangs on a chain around Anorak’s neck.</p>
         <p>The camera follows Anorak as he turns and continues farther into the dark cavern. A few
            seconds later, he arrives at a pair of massive wooden doors set into the cavern’s rocky
            wall. These doors are banded with steel, and there are shields and dragons carved into
            their surfaces. “I couldn’t playtest this particular game, so I worry that I may have
            hidden my Easter egg a little too well. Made it too diffi cult to reach. I’m not sure.
            If that’s the case, it’s too late to change anything now. So I guess we’ll see.”</p>
         <p>Anorak throws open the double doors, revealing an immense treasure room filled with
            piles of glittering gold coins and jewel-encrusted gob- lets.<note>Analysis reveals
               dozens of curious items hidden among the mounds of treasure, most notably: several
               early home computers (an Apple IIe, a Commodore 64, an Atari 800XL, and a TRS-80
               Color Computer 2), dozens of videogame controllers for a variety of game systems, and
               hundreds of polyhedral dice like those used in old tabletop role-playing
               games.</note> Then he steps into the open doorway and turns to face the viewer,
            stretching out his arms to hold open the giant double doors. <note>A freeze-frame of
               this scene appears nearly identical to a painting by Jeff Easley that appeared on the
               cover of the Dungeon Master’s Guide, a Dungeons &amp; Dragons rulebook published in
               1983.</note></p>
         <p>“So without further ado,” Anorak announces, “let the hunt for Hal- liday’s Easter egg
            begin!” Then he vanishes in a fl ash of light, leaving the viewer to gaze through the
            open doorway at the glittering mounds of treasure that lay beyond.</p>
         <p>Then the screen fades to black.</p>
         <figure/>

         <p>At the end of the video, Halliday included a link to his personal website, which had
            changed drastically on the morning of his death. For over a de- cade, the only thing
            posted there had been a short looping animation that showed his avatar, Anorak, sitting
            in a medieval library, hunched over a scarred worktable, mixing potions and poring over
            dusty spellbooks, with a large painting of a black dragon visible on the wall behind
            him.</p>
         <p>But now that animation was gone, and in its place there was a high- score list like
            those that used to appear in old coin-operated videogames.</p>
         <p>The list had ten numbered spots, and each displayed the initials JDH— James Donovan
            Halliday—followed by a score of six zeros. This high- score list quickly came to be
            known as “the Scoreboard.”</p>
         <p>Just below the Scoreboard was an icon that looked like a small leather- bound book,
            which linked to a free downloadable copy of Anorak’s Al- manac, a collection of hundreds
            of Halliday’s undated journal entries.</p>
         <p>The Almanac was over a thousand pages long, but it contained few de- tails about
            Halliday’s personal life or his day-to-day activities. Most of the entries were his
            stream-of-consciousness observations on various classic videogames, science-fi ction and
            fantasy novels, movies, comic books, and ’80s pop culture, mixed with humorous diatribes
            denouncing everything from organized religion to diet soda.</p>
         <p>The Hunt, as the contest came to be known, quickly wove its way into global culture.
            Like winning the lottery, fi nding Halliday’s Easter egg be- came a popular fantasy
            among adults and children alike. It was a game anyone could play, and at fi rst, there
            seemed to be no right or wrong way to play it. The only thing Anorak’s Almanac seemed to
            indicate was that a familiarity with Halliday’s various obsessions would be essential to
            fi nd- ing the egg. This led to a global fascination with 1980s pop culture. Fifty years
            after the decade had ended, the movies, music, games, and fashions of the 1980s were all
            the rage once again. By 2041, spiked hair and acid- washed jeans were back in style, and
            covers of hit ’80s pop songs by con- temporary bands dominated the music charts. People
            who had actually been teenagers in the 1980s, all now approaching old age, had the
            strange experience of seeing the fads and fashions of their youth embraced and studied
            by their grandchildren.</p>
         <p>A new subculture was born, composed of the millions of people who now devoted every free
            moment of their lives to searching for Halliday’s egg. At fi rst, these individuals were
            known simply as “egg hunters,” but this was quickly truncated to the nickname
            “gunters.”</p>
         <p>During the fi rst year of the Hunt, being a gunter was highly fashion- able, and nearly
            every OASIS user claimed to be one.</p>
         <p>When the fi rst anniversary of Halliday’s death arrived, the fervor sur- rounding the
            contest began to die down. An entire year had passed and no one had found anything. Not
            a single key or gate. Part of the prob- lem was the sheer size of the OASIS. It
            contained thousands of simulated worlds where the keys might be hidden, and it could
            take a gunter years to conduct a thorough search of any one of them.</p>
         <p>Despite all of the “professional” gunters who boasted on their blogs that they were
            getting closer to a breakthrough every day, the truth gradu- ally became apparent: No
            one really even knew exactly what it was they were looking for, or where to start
            looking for it.</p>
         <lg>
            <l>Another year passed.</l>
            <l>And another.</l>
            <l>Still nothing.</l>
         </lg>

         <p>The general public lost all interest in the contest. People began to as- sume it was all
            just an outlandish hoax perpetrated by a rich nut job. Oth- ers believed that even if
            the egg really did exist, no one was ever going to fi nd it. Meanwhile, the OASIS
            continued to evolve and grow in popular- ity, protected from takeover attempts and legal
            challenges by the ironclad terms of Halliday’s will and the army of rabid lawyers he had
            tasked with administering his estate.</p>
         <p>Halliday’s Easter egg gradually moved into the realm of urban legend, and the
            ever-dwindling tribe of gunters gradually became the object of ridicule. Each year, on
            the anniversary of Halliday’s death, newscasters jokingly reported on their continued
            lack of progress. And each year, more gunters called it quits, concluding that Halliday
            had indeed made the egg impossible to find.</p>
         <p>And another year went by.</p>
         <p>And another.</p>
         <p>Then, on the evening of February 11, 2045, an avatar’s name appeared at the top of the
            Scoreboard, for the whole world to see. After fi ve long years, the Copper Key had fi
            nally been found, by an eighteen-year-old kid living in a trailer park on the outskirts
            of Oklahoma City.</p>
         <p>That kid was me.</p>
         <p>Dozens of books, cartoons, movies, and miniseries have attempted to tell the story of
            everything that happened next, but every single one of them got it wrong. So I want to
            set the record straight, once and for all.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>